

PROFILE

More than 4 years of experience in Banking industry, gaining valuable transferable skills in relationship building, strategic planning, and project management. Strong track record of quickly learning and adapting in new and complex situations. Eager to leverage a diverse range of talents in a new and engaging professional setting. Committed to lifelong learning and personal development.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+63 9213810348

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jovernie-cano-6b71b1239/

EMAIL:

Jovcano28@gmail.com

ADDRESS:

Quezon City Philippines 1123

JOVERNIE CANO

EDUCATION

Polytechnic Universities of the PhilippinesJune 2001 to April 2006
Bachelor Degree in Business Teacher's Education

WORK EXPERIENCE

Recoveries Officer

Australian and New Zealand Bank (ANZ)

Apr 2021 to Apr 2022

- Responsible for settling and recovering on debts in the post charge-off space.
- · Recover credit losses for ANZ
- Make sound financial decisions based on the information available using CADs(discretion) and initiative
- Field all customer enquiries (whether internal customers or third parties ie. mercantile agents, solicitors), providing accurate and relevant information which shows understanding of customer needs and expectation.
- High concern for legislative and regulatory requirements

Credit Analyst

Australian and New Zealand Bank (ANZ)

Aug 2020 to Apr 2021

- Ensuring that the information and privacy of clients and well secure
- Action customer request (whether internal customers or third parties ie. credit repair, solicitors, credit bureau) providing relevant documents ie. legal letters (Default notice,

HOBBIES

- Love to travel in different places to explore sceneries and learn other countries culture.
- Playing console and mobile games, especially role-playing games.
- Doing cross-stitches mostly angel's design.
- Reading books.

SKILLS

- Computer Savvy
- Proficient in Microsoft office tools (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access)
- Google Workspace

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Attention to details
- Excellent written and communication skills
- Ability to work under pressure
- Ability to multitask

- Letter of demand, pre default warning, Letter of Default), call recording.
- Make sound judgement in reversing customers repayment history status and/or credit listing by conducting a thorough investigation of customer banking history and if all appropriate action was taken by the bank.

Collection Officer

Australian and New Zealand Bank (ANZ)

Apr 2019 to Aug 2020

- Take inbound call for mortgage customers.
- Arrange payment plan appropriate to customer financial situation.
- Coordinate with other team, if necessary, in servicing customers need.
- Apply credit adjustment in line with company discretion limit in resolving customer's concern.

Customer Service

Australian and New Zealand Bank (ANZ)

Dec 2017 to Apr 2019

- Making sure that customers account is secure and protected from possible fraudulent calls
- Help customers with complaints and questions
- Give customers information about products and services
- walk through customers in registration of internet banking, resetting password and provide general information on how internet banking works.

Senior Logistics Officer

TPG Telecom

Jan 2009 to Dec 2017

- Implement and control the efficient, effective forward and reverse flow of our products and services in order to meet our client's expectations.
- Conducts and optimizes the steady flow of material through a network of transport links and ensures they arrive in time.
- Supervises the daily production and distribution planning for our products and services.
- Coordinate with our suppliers, distributors, and customers creating communication channels for critical information and operational improvements for the effective delivery of the required service.

- Directly confers with our third-party wholesale providers in regards with investigating and analyzing complex issues that may arise especially with our services.
- Communicates with our client's needs, through email and phone by filtering their issues and distributing them accordingly to the appropriate department concern.
- Conducts continues forecast for other internal departments in relation to system failure and other possible logistical issues that may arise due to unseen circumstances.
- Supervises logistical data gathering, review and analysis and provide recommendations with upper management to assure optimal performance in conformance to efficiency, quality and productivity.
- Supervises training for new and up-coming logistics officer.

Customer Service Escalation Officer Etelecare Global Solutions

Jan 2007 to Dec 2009

- Take escalated call to customer's asking for a supervisor.
- Provide the best and adequate resolution to customer's enquiry.
- Coordinate with other department if necessary to resolve customer's concern.

Data Analyst

Accenture

July 2006 to Jan 2007

• Audit customer submitted documents to verify if it's matches system records and make necessary correction if needed.